Welcome back to the angel debates
the devil
if you know the story
it is it is with translation yes it is
the current cast yes really
easy slowly
I like big breaths
pauses
like me and caught in the announcement
for this program
we have this
is it rating started to read with
my teacher is no robot clubs a
day in that was about
30 years ago
and he said I want to
teach this unusual book
very that and providers and wanted to
know what this is for a month said that
this is
the poem was written about 350 years ago
or you could say 175 and is from the
first which name as uniformity were
written his name was Lutz
Wicke
I am alive who it is great is a
fantastic teacher
and I have been learning about it for three years now
20 years ago in countries with grades
he is a great
funnel we have
translated his poems his secret reports
I have also translated hunter of an
opinion student Johnstone a
bad boy  First published without
asking me,
even though they are secret poems. You
can probably put them somewhere
[music].
And it's very, very nice greetings about
his secret learning and his secret
packs. Then he
wrote great philosophy books. I love
his explanation
[music]
that our body reveals itself in a
living diamond. If
you are successful on these
paths,
and I don't think you can
find it anywhere else. It's written so clearly that the
beginning of the transformation from 4
to 5,
successfully sharing a part of
one day going through it. He
also wrote a very famous lamp poem,
it was called "Success."
It means "The Path to Bliss."
It can also be translated as "The
Simple Activity." That's a beginning.
These are the first three of the 18
courses on the Diamond Way. Only six years have passed since
Tim and I started correcting us. We're talking about
ways to
make these courses accessible to more people, and
we'll talk more about it.
I thought we could
look at some of this poem. I started
reading it eleven years ago.
Also translated.
We had  A Phoenix in Arizona will have
a program for it. There's
a very fast one. There's a
very nice public garden
there with Boeing. We actually do
n't have much rain in the special
garden. It's full of trees, actually more like
cacti, but they are very beautiful, and the
garden allowed us to have a program there.
I started
teaching there eleven years ago,
and when my teacher taught me this book,
we had some
obstacles.
Hey
sir,
this is an obstacle,
some obstacles to finishing this book.
So, a little bit like
finishing it together.
He passed away,
and I hope, I hope, I will finish the
whole thing and translate it
because it's so beautiful
about telling this story. The angel
here, in our case, is the understanding
of the voices.
In the end, in the poem, the angel is very, very
beautiful
and wise in the
[music].
That's the good side of our spirit.
I don't know if it's in all countries,
but in my country,
when we grow up,
they show us pictures
of, like in the advertisement for this
program, on one side of the head,
he's
also there.  The other side is nicer,
my devil would always
make me, through my angel, always want to make
me
eat vegetarian things and vegetables, and they
argue most days about it, saying it would
n't be right now
to eat in Dohna. We've forgotten for a long time,
for two or three weeks now, we can
forget that. I understand, they're
not so healthy, but
innovation is one of those
pleasures in life, and you can have
one now and then, it's quite alright,
not so bad. And
then the angel says, no, no, no,
everything you eat becomes part of you, you are
what you eat,
and every time something unhealthy,
it's a part of your body. Yesterday,
for example,
[music]
gave a
very interesting lesson,
yes, now they say you are what you eat.
That's a very famous saying,
and
what you eat determines what a body becomes,
so my body today, for example,
[music],
I'm doing a great one for my
wife.
We both got groups this
week, and I've only just recovered from it.
as the
first and she herself a little bit more
and that week for her
okay the devil will try to
persuade you to eat a doner kebab and
Engelberg no no let's rather have
vegetables
and then they will discuss after all
your mind and that is what
this poem is going on
besides angel especially the
wisdom of the pen is the firm the
understanding of the poses
I want to
teach the pen every time
I go into Zoom Q3 and you to
your it
is a it is a proof
if everyone in the world
becomes ecological if we
become completely logical still
after I have explained the pen to you
Moritz
pieces here these parts then I see sets
when I this that you one and show
they see no pen and it
really sounds childish bees little
story that one tells a child
when one tells a good night story that one
tells a child maybe one can
write good night stories book schoolchildren the pen is called it sounds
maybe we would then have a
good night story but it is
not now it is a one hundred percent
proof  If your mind
is truly clear and sane, then it
can see. It's already a
hundred percent proof that
things come from us; they don't come
from their own side.
And I know that sounds very simple.
[Music]
Repeated a thousand times. I know how
likely you are. Are you already tired of
hearing it? But if you truly understand now,
then you know that you can change this whole world.
And we have this word in the
Buddhist mandala.
It means there is no war, there is no
disease. It is
when
pen is possible.
If
I have heard from simple people,
heaven is boring,
everything,
that this will stand for the explanation and the
definition of dependency.
That is, that is, it's like being... You can't
copy anyone if you're not
called a banana.
That's not true. You can blaspheme; it
tastes good
even if you're not called a banana.
So it is possible.
If it
comes from me, then I can
create a perfect world, and we should do it.
We should make it happen. There's
the Nivea Meter. Paradise. They've
already done it; they had this
on the way, not long before,
hours ago. They had exactly the  Same
classes you know, I'm
great, different from
us. We've stayed the same,
these Buddhas, and where the sun shines,
they started like us, they're not
different from us, how they
started. I always think we are, like they are,
we are the
students in the last row, the one who
takes it a little slower, and the
students in the first class, in the
first row, they always raise their hands and say, "
I know, I know, those are them,"
says Reh, "They
are, they've already graduated."
We're rather slow people in the
class,
we can still catch up. This
kind of instruction wo
n't help us catch up,
and I think we'll live in a perfect
world. I've seen these worlds,
you can do that to other people. It's
fun
together, let's do it, does the fish
pass,
this time with the angel, run to the
meeting, said other shoulders,
team spirit,
this day, you and I are the same.
We have the angel on one side, on the
other side, created, back again,
and I, all day long,
in the files, books, every now and then,
they say
it's possible that you can people  You
can read their thoughts if you meditate
and meditate yourself, then you can learn
to do that if it flows really well a few times, for example,
if you do a yoga
mast-wise. You can
learn to read other people's thoughts,
but it's not that much fun. You
might think it's fun, but
it's actually not. It's rather
sad what arguments people have
inside their minds, all that
fuss and all those thoughts about
other people's minds. If you
could really read their thoughts, it wouldn't be
fun at all
because we all have flaws and
shortcomings, and they argue all day long.
So let's look at the book. This
is the 15th time I've read it.
The Federation doesn't teach
[Music].
We'll have
33 more teachings,
maybe in the next two years,
and then we'll be finished.
Then we can publish it. The
Catholic Press can
publish it for billions of dollars.
I think it needs a
comment because it's a very difficult
book.
I have something else to say.
Above the engine, I like this
story about the car the most, that it's
my favorite story. He was
on retreat in one go, not in
a cave.
If you ever have a long one,
most people have to cook for you
because you shouldn't spend time buying
food. You're
not allowed to go out, you can't come.
So he has someone who does it like him.
Everyone who participates,
and this person left a note there, a
post. They communicate via
writing. They try to talk to me,
and the food buyer left a
note there. There's bad
news. You have to move your retreat.
You can't finish it here at this altitude.
Written back, why
the food shopping? Because there's going to be a
world war right here in
these parts, under the cave. It's a war
that will take place tomorrow.
Two Armenians are coming here,
two generals for two years, and the
world won't fight. Many people
will die.
This shouldn't be here because if that
happens, you shouldn't be here in
this cave.
Can you imagine
that the first volume, but only
as we think, he's sure. Brussels,
I should have gone away today.
Should have had
my meditation-  pillow life and
my brother's image and is right running
I should go to another building because
I think we would do the same and
that he worries
falling asleep and has been worrying more and more
even if they will
tomorrow war breaks out in this in this
part then many many
people will die
[Music]
that it is not green I should do something about
that he
tomorrow he broke off his retreat
and he wrote a note
on his food body
the famous noise on
and he said
later in the day
bring me two sacks full of gold bring me
yellow gold
and let's try to stop this war
the armies
facing each other stood Norm to fight ran out
of his cave and he and he
sent to the battlefield
between the two armies he said he
was already very famous at the time a
very famous teacher
and he says we will if you want to
kill each other then you must kill
me first and I will
not move and the armies had a
big split both sides of the army let
me dictate the two
devices come to me he says and let's
discuss this and  They spoke
and the two gladly took the dean to the middle of
the battlefield
and he said let's sit down and they
sat down and he said I have a
suggestion for us about this war
and the two generals Frank take what
is your suggestion
and he said I am a pretty
famous lama and I have people
who always bring me money and gold
I have the two big sacks full of
gold with gold coins
my suggestion is one tell this
general the
other
this general
and then why don't you just go
home and relax and don't make a secret of it
they were very happy about the two
sacks full of gold and they went home
against Duncan and
everyone lived happily
it is so impressive how in war I
can read I love him he is brave
and he is so smart
and he is such a beautiful forward-thinking
person I will you here
we let ourselves through various I don't know
how far we get Grant
always tells stories
he teaches me very quickly I
think we will have a short session
right and then say
but two sessions this apartment do
in my time in 20 minutes
We will
and answer is that OK team that sounds
very good
OK
let's take a short break can't
Veronika soup to backgrounds and then
we have another class
OK I
wanted to
use instruction for this
[Music]
invite my friends in the huge area in Sedona so that we can meet up again
it's a lot of fun when we get
together in Konz at the college in
Singapore instruction
but I think I have I am
still infected from the curve I had this
week I feel great I have
recovered from everything but I don't want
others to get infected so
we do
and that we go there
when everything is safe then we can
all sit together again OK let's go will you
OK
let's go through these parts
in Buddhism we say if you are quiet
then if you were very generous
and if you have them what
is the first perfection many say
generosity some say giving
I take
details name if you really
had your money and your time heals and there
your wisdom partly with other people
after you die you will then be as a
theme  reborn
and that means
I don't know if you see these
people with Superman citizens
[Music]
in the goal because these are people like you,
which
I believe, I believe these swimmers were made
by people who still
remember their past lives.
I believe the people who make these movies, I think they
still remember a little bit of
their past lives.
And if we plant great seeds
by sharing everything we have with
other people,
because after they can die, they will
reach heaven.
And of course, we think it is, because
even these beings die after a
while and they consume their goodness back then.
We believe it's not a good place to go.
When we watch these movies, we can't, how did it come about?
We watch,
we can't perceive them directly,
but they exist.
If you, if you could meet them, it feels like
the power
we stand with.
It feels like their
superpowers are in the air, to fly to the air
or fight against the
villains. As if these
powerful self-existence, like the
founder coming from his side,
but
[Music]
in his whole life
countless lives of it  If you're alive now,
if you're listening to me now,
then you've had a... life will come.
If something happens,
it can also just happen.
If the computer doesn't work,
if your car
sounds strange, then you should get it fixed.
It won't get better if
a car makes strange noises.
If a cell phone or computer
sounds strange,
you should get it fixed immediately.
Then it will happen again.
If we're alive now, if
you were born here, a man, if
you were born here once, then there's
nothing to do.
If your car breaks down on Monday and
makes a noise, then it will also be broken on Tuesday.
If you were born here in this world once,
then it can happen
again. It can happen a second
time. It can happen millions of times
because time is endless.
If we read a story
about a teacher whom we believe to be
a very special person, who
was very generous and
shared everything, and after they
died,
when will these seeds
create this world of gods? How does it
behave?
But then he says,
if this demigod
really exists from within himself,
how do they create
this life then?  for sea up and how
can they go to another place
if this pen out of
how fat ahead it exists then
can how the children choose what would be
impossible
if he gets from his own time
you can never choose the children that
would be impossible
time out comes
then they can't die and
then they can't change and
what does the angel have
I like happy the class of today
English speaks often not often she is very
shy
she doesn't speak to the this time
but here she says look here
if the pen
it exists
if the manager out of the human
how can they then die
means here how can they then die
and be reborn and this
whole face
about today they
discuss
how it happens what what happens will
us because we
die
and it's really a strange thing
when I was at the prince without water
and it's one of the best universities
in the world and I really believe that
then I spent five years there
and there isn't a single chance
how to die
that's totally funny
that
we have 36 million dollars every year
and there's no class on how to
die properly that's surprising would everyone have to
die
that would be out by  If you were to
build a university and not
include toilets,
sooner or later you simply have to rely on
talent. Therefore, don't
build even a lightning-fast annex without a toilet
because after two or three hours the
world needs a toilet. So don't be
stupid if you need a university.
If you build buildings, then
you should think ahead.
If you teach people about life, you
also have to teach them about pressure,
because otherwise the
teaching is incomplete. And the angel says,
now he's looking at me.
If you're exposed but don't
exist, how can you die? And
what happens to your poor when you go into
your next life?
The places should be
19 or 30 years in the future.
If someone says, "
Pack your suitcase," and you say, "Tanja
is never ready, where am I going now?" Don't worry, pitch your suitcase
somewhere. And when am I going? It was in
the next few years. But ask about your
suitcase, and it's already packed.
But if you don't ask where it's going,
and if you don't ask where you
should pack your suitcase, if you
don't ask this question, then you will  You
for this life is so short this
life is over before you're a hard worker at
25 and not today for 60
and a tree a little filled
I was shocked you should get
ready
you will stay here everyone someone
will move on what I can carry on
what can I do at this time so
let's move on to verse
and now the devil
he says
every star every
exercise also came here was
star don't be so stupid
the last time performance disappeared did you come
back too you're
here don't let yourself get through of course what so
somewhere go where came here
if this can happen once then
it can happen a second time
everyone knows that
and everyone should get their car repaired the
first choice if it makes a strange noise
as what does the devil say yes people
die and they move on
but says the pen itself exists of
itself so you cannot
die
the pen of itself exists exist
But you ca
n't change from within yourself, then there's
no reason why you should change.
That's a really difficult idea.
If the pen exists from within itself,
as we believe,
then it shouldn't change, and
who should never advertise?
If the ink is in the pen, then it should
never run out.
If that proves it, everything makes no
sense.
The pen comes from the public, we made it,
bought the boss.
I didn't say that the pen can't
change, and that's why
we have to buy more.
At the bachelor's, to you:
if the pen comes from the factory, then it ca
n't change,
and we should run out like the ink.
I never said that. Of
course, the boss is made in the factory.
When you write,
the animal comes out and writes on the
paper, and then at some point, in Delius,
buy a new one.
[Music]
I said
the pen can't change,
but you think so
because the Frankfurt Foundation doesn't come, but
the question doesn't arise. You don't ask
why the
pen to the year,
and that's not it. If you want to
lead a happy life
and have a successful death, that's a  Something strange
happened, so if you want to have a
happy life
and a successful death,
then you have to ask yourself where you come
from,
not how you came into this world,
but why you are in this world.
If you ask away, the pen, into the
shop, or comes the year, drive, and
evil, became from the Middle East to
Japan, shop, and the factory made the pen from
the oil, it
certainly comes, yes, Greece,
and I say, but no, you say to me,
how did the pen come to me, not myself,
why, so, I
had to understand,
again, the pen came to me, the
narrator, finished, the pile, ship,
sent to America, did you buy it, yes, yes,
understand it, how, but why, I, why, I,
our, still in
this pen, has come to me,
Hescheler,
they make thousands of pens every day,
some, to some questions, there are no
answers,
the film, did you lose your job,
the student with her, worrying
about these really strange
questions, don't worry,
why the pen, to become, have,
use, a woman,
August,
there should be, I ask, Rome, does
a car today make strange noises,
why, although  Is the computer nowadays like
nothing, why, like, yeah,
I turn the car on and then through
signs, kilometers, or makes strange
noises,
what is it, like, but the question is, why
my car,
the car is still running, such a
great new car, none of them are
broken, why my car,
a real beat,
then you have to ask yourself why I don't, like,
that's simply, the engine has
given up the ghost because something
is clogged, that's true, like your
cars break down, but that's not,
but tell me when, and my car, why does my car
have engine problems, and teams
on honey, and Zetsche's car too,
you have to ask these questions,
it's important,
it's super important, I don't know what
she's doing today, I have to go
to college today so
I can finish the sum for my wife.
[Music]
Yeah, you think ahead, planned like Burn Day,
a part,
but that finally has to go on the journey
and dies, 'that will happen,'
100 percent. I don't know
if I'll start college today, do
n't know if the soup will burn or
not, but I know I'm going to die, which
certainly
means that, we should consider the
Make a fire for that and we have to ask why
we die and not how we died. We do that,
and what do we do then? In the next
class, will
you ask me the questions? I think we'll
drive for another 15 minutes.
We have a few questions
ahead of us. Now, so far on
schedule, like car fire,
then we'll now do 15 minutes of
answering questions, and then there will be a 15-minute
break.
Each question is like this, one out, what not, that on
or off.
[Music]
Hotel
[Laughter]
With us, it's immense.
We were too classy.
If I were the pen story,
we can apply that to everyone.
How do we find it on people who experience
domestic violence, live in war,
the deep grief alone? That's a
great question.
You know that I lived in a moral
monastery for 25 years near
New York, but the whole neighborhood
is Mongolian. They are all gestures,
and life is about 15 possible acts.
Very old Mongolian Munich. I
studied there. The port lived for 25 years
with my teacher.
I came from Princeton.
I should, I wanted a delicious
Vista,
I was accepted,
I was very active in the church,
and Prince didn't have a really great
cathedral, the stupid steam, very
similar to the Dame in Paris. I
think they stole the view, the plan from
there, so very beautiful, and
the music is very beautiful.
It's quiet
and very expensive, maybe the dollar.
So I went from Princeton directly to
Mongolia, fighting
[music],
and there were many great
Buddhist state wave pools,
but there were also some terrible
paintings, like all of them,
and the music was...
I couldn't meditate. It was like
in the Second World War. When
studying, I was asked
how I could understand these terrible
paintings and these sounds. I had to guess
and meditate, and he said, "
Every culture has its own way," and
banks, and the Mogo in Mongolia is...
then it would be a wonderful church. It's
just a very different culture,
different from Prince, and it's also
wonderfully relaxed.
And then on the teacher's throne is
a classic,
that's the Nazi symbol from Germany.
The Nazis stole the six
million people who fought in a war
in which 130 million
people died. His father is
because the symbol comes from ancient
India
and it is a very beautiful
symbol. It means long life. The
swastika means long life.
And guest rooms on the
teacher's seat for 2000 years before
Hitler and before the long and before the
Nazis.
He breathes, everything is explained and was
really still meaningful. Maybe Hitler
stole the symbol,
and then one day Jews came to the
temple and waited if they could look at the temple.
We thought, oh my God, this will be
a problem
because I was the youngest person, soft,
the tour guide,
so I had to lead them and
explain everything.
And before they, my teacher
sent a
hidden box. What tickers have to
take purpose and push, but
under the chair, don't show them.
Meyer says they won't
understand, otherwise they will believe
that they are Nazis and therefore bad
people. Just hide it,
hide the box.  It's not them,
so I want to earn them,
and then he said some things
are too early, they're not ready
for
this symbol, seen their whole lives,
and even if they search for it, they wo
n't feel comfortable in our film.
I want you to hide it, and I did
too,
and only time will pass, and it's exciting,
happy,
and then they left again.
What do we have that, what Tiger put back on the
diploma?
Why am I telling you this?
In Buddhism, we understand that there is a
time when the student
isn't ready for some things, when we do
n't talk about certain things yet because
the student isn't ready for them.
And I believe that, for example, children
get into car accidents and burn,
little children.
Why are so many children sexually
abused or otherwise exploited, or
physically beaten?
Why does this happen? What is the reason
for it,
and better to give a reason for it?
Because everything has a cause. There is
nothing in the universe that doesn't have a
cause. Everything is
caused. Everything has a maintenance, and
not 9W. Do
n't tell me how the child
was abused. They
've gone somewhere and it's
evil.  A man came and then they were
n't needed, that's how it is, but how to
tell why this child and
not others.
In Buddhism,
we have answers to these questions,
and that's why we are all here, and that's why
this class would like to meet today.
We feel
what we can choose, the answers we
can find out,
but there is a time when people
are not yet ready for the answer.
There is a time, or simply
showing compassion, and when we give them love,
establish a connection. There is
n't always an immediate
answer
if he thought the student was
n't ready to hear it yet. There is
a reason why children die in
car accidents when they are two years old, or
burn in the fire. There is
a reason why
some children are
abused and other children are not. Of
course, there is a reason for this,
but in our tradition,
the great teachers say,
perhaps the student is not yet
ready to
give it, at least the embrace,
like in life.
You can explain it to them later when
they have more needs. Then you can tell them
about past lives and about seeds,
why everything has a cause,
but you have to do it at the right time,
and if the parents are suffering,
not at the right time,
then you have to  Hiding the ticker and
then you just have to take it in your arms,
get it, and make it feel
comfortable, but of course, everything has
a cause.
I recently
met someone who said, "
Why did the children have problems?" She was
pregnant,
ate her pizza with too spicy sauce, and that's why
the child was unhappy.
Because we don't understand that there's a
time before that, and we have to learn to
say such funny things as, "This child
is a little
confused because the
mother ate pizza during pregnancy." I mean, something like that
comes up,
and of course, it doesn't make sense.
And I think the brother
always checked out the students first,
and my teacher, whom I believe was a brother, taught me that you don't
always have to tell everything on the first day. That
will help the student become a hero at their level,
and later you can teach them
more because everything has a cause.
Now, another question would come up:
at the beginning, you taught us a wonderful
story about the first branch lama.
We stopped the speed. There were
some questions because of the shared one, the one
in  living in war zones or where the
risk of war is very high,
and they want to
know how we can prevent it.
He knows the story: I was in
Princeton during the Vietnam War,
and the war affected me very strongly.
I fought against this war;
I was even briefly sidelined
because my wife and I tried to
sabotage a bombing.
We sat peacefully in front of the doors
and prevented the
workers in the factories from doing it. Then
the police stopped me. I spent a
short time in jail,
and I met with a group of students,
and we all wanted the crisis to end. There
were 1,000 students in the building,
and then one of them said, "
Let's throw his bomb at
the university president's office," and
that totally
shocked me. Then I raised my hand in
front of 1,000 students and
said, "I don't understand it."
He would do the same thing to everyone.
He would throw the bomb, report it, name it, and so you could
avoid it. Would you
start school? That is  But the same thing
confused me a lot,
and then I was really wet with cells.
Later,
I consistently supported the anti-war movement for 45 years,
and then,
if a person didn't really do much,
thousands of
kilometers away from Vietnam, I did
n't know how to end the war. That's why
I was really quite
disappointed and didn't do much anymore.
And after I studied the apprenticeship
with my teacher
and how to open the seeds,
and also the result, why space
before my environment, my world
comes from me, neither pen, my world around
its conflict,
and also very serious conflicts
from me,
and when I listen to the news today,
I listened to the news about
these problems yesterday when I
drove from the classes last night,
and you always have to remember, this comes
from me, this problem comes from me,
and because it comes from me,
I help to eliminate it.
You are never helpless. If the pen was there,
then you are never helpless. You can
always help,
everyone in the world,
help to eliminate this conflict. We
can all help,
manufacturers, as always, one, a
small person, and it  It's thousands of
miles long, what can I do?
It's still the same old story.
These
inhibitions, these conflicts, which are really
very serious. 15 for everyone, for the whole
world, each of
us, each of us
has planted seeds,
probably for this conflict. We see in it that
we are spoiled
because it comes from us, and because it
comes from me, to
say to a person, I can do something about it,
and I do
n't have to blow up the school or go to jail.
I can resolve this situation,
and how is it quite simple?
We see people who don't talk to each other;
they are quite selfish. We do
n't think about the other side, what the other
side needs. All this
because I have
planted such seeds. My whole heart, all day long,
I take care of
myself, and I don't care
about other people. There are so
many of them, millions of people who
have nothing to eat today. Millions.
I can stop the war. I can
do something if I try
not to plant seeds in my name this time. If
I argue with someone, there is
someone with your life in  In
my life
now, I'm afraid of myself.
I don't want to hurt other people,
but there are even people who
need my love, my
attention, for whom
I need care.
If I simply take care of a few men, a
few people in my
life who have problems, especially
people who are afraid of me,
and with that, I destroy the seeds of the
great conflict. So, everyone
present today, you have the power to
stop this conflict. You can do something
because it comes from your seeds,
and that's totally upsetting. To put
someone on someone you have problems with, or to take care
of someone who
believes you want to hurt them,
you show the project,
and what will change the seeds of
seeing the great conflict? And when we
come back to the text, we also see
that in his future life, what kind of
conflict, what kind of opinions, will there be
in a future life? You
can fix it now. If you
can change your whole world,
then it's easy
to eliminate a small conflict. A few things have to be discussed
now.
We'll meet again in
15 minutes, no
matter where in the world. In 15
minutes, we'll continue. Until then...